# Alexey Li

 ♦ Seoul, South Korea
 ☑ leealkon@gmail.com
 ↓ +82-10-7759-7988
 ♦ portfolio
 in alexey-li
 ♦ vlewv11

# Summary

With a strong focus on **AI**, **Computer Vision**, and **Classic ML**, I specialize in building end-to-end pipelines from data engineering to model deployment. I have more than **3 years** of professional experience, working with 2D and 3D data, **CUDA-accelerated modeling**, and model **optimization** including **quantization** and **deployment** with **ONNX** and **TensorRT**.

## Skills

Programming: Python, MySQL.

Data Processing: Pandas, NumPy, OpenCV, PIL, re, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Bokeh, PointCloud. Model Development: Scikit-Learn, TensorFLow, Keras, PyTorch, ONNX, TensorRT, CUDA.

Tools: Git, Docker, Linux, SSH, JIRA, Confluence.

Additional Frameworks: PyQT, Flask, TKinter, ROS2.

Other: Quantization, Pruning, 4D Image Radar, Lidar, Projection, Classification, Regression, Detection, Clustering.

Language Proficiency: Russian – Native, English – Advanced, Korean – Intermediate (TOPIK 4).

# Experience

AI Researcher

DeepFusionAI

Seoul, South Korea

June 2023 - Present

- Cleaned and preprocessed **4D Image Radar PointCloud** data to improve data quality. Transformed an **unsupervised** learning dataset into a **semi-supervised** format, eventually achieving a fully labeled dataset for training 3D object detection models.
- Modified an internal labeling tool by integrating **3D-to-2D projection** using camera calibration matrices, improving the accuracy and efficiency of annotation processes on **250%** in average.
- o Optimized the data preprocessing pipeline, achieving a 3x increase in speed for model input preparation.
- Developed various 3D detection models on point cloud data, exploring fusion techniques with images to enhance model
  performance. Implemented real-time ROS2 integration, publishing fused 3D detection and 2D BEV map outputs for
  downstream autonomous system applications.

ML Engineer NOTA

Sankt-Petersburg, Russia Jan 2022 - Mar 2023

- Developed a video processing software to extract statistical data from security camera footage, leveraging YOLOv10 for object detection and ByteTrack for multi-object tracking within predefined regions of interest (ROIs).
- $\circ$  Optimized polygon-based attendance checks by reducing intersection calculations to O(1) time, resulting in a 3x performance improvement.
- Optimized, **quantized** the model, converting it to **ONNX** and **TensorRT** format for efficient inference and deploying it with reduced computational overhead. Achieved a **4x inference speed** improvement per frame, enabling real-time processing. Reached an **mAP** (Mean Average Precision) of **0.86** for the human class, significantly improving detection performance in surveillance scenarios.

#### **Projects**

FlappyBird AI Bot

Project Link 🗹

• FlappyBird using NEAT (NeuroEvolution with Augmented Topologies) framework with integrated **Genetic Algorithm**, tuning the model and population genomes as soon it reaches the game **score 500**.

#### Mail Box Spam Filter

Project Link

• Implemented a spam filter using a combination of **Naive Bayes** and **Random Forest** models. The dataset for this project was manually created by labeling every message as either "spam" or "ham" (not spam) based on a personal mailbox. The dataset includes several features: username, email domain, subject, and text body.

## Education

## Pusan National University

Busan, South Korea

BS in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2019 - Sep 2023

o Thesis: "Tailoring Music for Every Generation". Built CNN age recognition model VGG19 with 6.32 MAE for every age, connected Spotify recommendation system to listen demos (Project link ∠)